modahealth.com 2019-12-19

# Moda Health Web Privacy

Moda Health appreciates your use of our web site and respects your privacy.

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site:

Personal information is information that is unique to you and can be used to identify you, such as name, address, telephone, social security number, etc. We do not collect your personal information unless you provide it to us voluntarily. We use your personal information to send you requested information about our services or to respond to your questions. We use unique identifiers such as social security number or plan identification to verify your identity and provide you with customized information.

Non-personal information includes your IP address, browser type and version, which pages you view on our site, what site you came to us from and what site you go to when you leave. We use non-personal information to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. Non-personal information is also used to assemble broad demographic information and may be shared with various parties. We look at aggregate activity such as total hits and frequently viewed pages to allow us to continue to improve our web site to meet our customers' needs.

## Children's Information

Based on the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will not collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen.

## Security

This site has standard security measures in place such as firewalls to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under our control.

## Future Changes

We may find the need to update or change our privacy statement in the future. We reserve the right to make such changes and will post a new privacy statement should that situation occur.

## Email

The confidentiality of information sent over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. Although we take reasonable precautions to safeguard the confidentiality of your request, Moda Health cannot guarantee the security of any email correspondence sent to us. Please do not use email to send us information that you consider confidential. If you prefer to use telephone, or mail to contact us, you may reach us at:

_Dental_  
Moda Health  
601 SW Second Avenue  
Portland, OR 97204-3156  
(503)228-6554  
1-800-452-1058  |  _Medical_  
Moda Health  
PO Box 40384  
Portland, OR 97240  
(503)228-6554  
1-877-605-3229  
---|---  
  
## Browser and encryption FAQs

  * What is encryption and why do I need it?
  * What else is required to use this site?
  * Why can't I access any secure pages on the Moda Health website with Internet Explorer?

What is encryption and why do I need it?

Changes in federal law are affecting requirements to ensure that member information is kept confidential and the transmission of that information is secure over the Internet. To comply with the current requirements for transmission over the Internet, the browser you use must be capable of supporting encryption and de-encryption.

Encryption is the process of converting data into a secure format for transmission. Encryption scrambles data that is sent from Moda Health to you. Your browser must be capable of decrypting, or unscrambling, the data. To do this, you will need a 128-bit-capable browser. 

Browsers with 128-bit encryption provide the best protection when transmitting confidential data over the Internet. You must update your browser to 128-bit encryption or you will not be able to use some areas of the Moda Health website.

Return to top

What else is required to use this site?

Some of our applications require the following: 

  * Adobe Acrobat reader, which is a [free download from Adobe](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep2.html)
  * JavaScript turned on through your browser
  * Cookies turned on through your browser

For help with any of these requirements, please contact your local technical resources team or contact your Internet service provider.

Return to top

Why can't I access any secure pages on the Moda Health website with Internet Explorer?

Internet Explorer has security settings that may need to be updated. The common error message you may see is “The page cannot be displayed. Cannot find server or DNS Error.” Please visit Microsoft's [support page](http://support.microsoft.com/support/kb/articles/Q181/1/47.asp) for more information.

Return to top
